Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Media and News TAM.503
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media and News
2007-
TAM.503
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library, which was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived News Web sites of entities that create, gather and disseminate to the public news, research, personal opinion and other content that reflects a left/progressive viewpoint. Websites represented include those of periodicals, radio stations, blogs, and other news websties that publish such content, but that are irregularly, but typically frequently updated. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Contents Note
Contains periodically archived News Web sites of entities that create, gather and disseminate to the public news, research, personal opinion and other content that reflects a left / progressive viewpoint. The content of these sites are primarily general interest or multi-issue; similar single issue sites are usually found in the other topically based web archives created by the Tamiment Library, NYU. Websites represented include those of periodicals, radio stations, blogs, and other news websites that publish such content, but that are irregularly, but typically frequently updated. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the web page Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
Alternative mass media |z United States.; Alternative mass media.; Blogs |z United States.; Blogs.; Civil rights |v Periodicals.; Civil rights |z United States |v Periodicals.; Electronic journals |z United States.; Electronic journals.; Electronic newspapers |z United States.; Electronic newspapers.; News web sites |z United States.; News Web sites.; United States |x Foreign relations |v Periodicals.; United States |x Politics and government |v Periodicals.; United States |x Social conditions |v Periodicals.; World politics |v Periodicals.
- Alternative Media Web and News Web Archive, 2007-
  - A-Infos Radio Project, 03/20/2009-
  - Against the Grain, 12/05/2011-
  - Alternative Press Center, 10/02/2007-
  - Alternative Radio, 6/20/2011-
  - AlterNet, 10/02/2007-
  - AltWeeklies.com, 4/25/2012-
  - American Prospect, 11/19/2010-
  - Arts Engine, 10/21/2011-
  - Autonomedia, 09/21/2007-
  - Axis of Logic, 07/26/2009-
  - Billboard Liberation Front, 08/15/2009-3/16/2010
  - Buzzflash, 4/22/2012-
  - Center for Media Justice, 10/20/2011-
  - Collapse Network, 7/15/2011-
  - Color Lines, 10/25/2011-
  - Common Dreams, 10/02/2007-
  - CounterPunch, 07/29/2009-
  - Deep Dish TV Network, 07/31/2009-
  - Deep Dish Waves of Change, 10/12/2011-
  - Democracy Now!, 10/02/2007-
  - Democracy Underground, 4/27/2012-
  - DIRELAND: Politics and Media Analysis and Commentary from Veteran Political Journalist Doug Ireland, 7/19/2010-
  - Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting, 10/02/2007-
  - Fighting Bob, 1/06/2012-
  - First Voices Indigenous Radio (FVIR), 5/22/2011-
  - Free Press, 2/01/2012-
  - Free Speech TV, 08/14/2009-
  - From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog, 07/26/2009-
  - From The Wilderness: Information on Peak Oil, Sustainablility, and the events surrounding 9/11, 07/27/2009
  - GlobalInfo.org, 08/06/2009-
  - Global Revolution TV, 11/11/2011-
  - Global Voices, 10/14/2011-
  - Grand Rapids Institute for Information Democracy, 7/16/2010-
  - Hightower Lowdown, 1/06/2012-
  - In These Times, 12/07/2011-
  - Independent Media Center, 10/02/2007-
  - Institute for War and Peace Reporting, 4/3/2012-
  - Interactivist Network, 09/21/2007-
  - IPS North America, 7/9/2011-
  - KPFA 94.1 FM Berkeley, 10/02/2007-
  - KPFK 90.7 FM, 7/16/2011-
  - KPFT 90.1 FM, 7/17/2011-
  - La Lutta New Media Collective, 05/07/2008-
  - Left Business Observer, 4/26/2012-
  - Media Action Grassroots Network, 10/14/2011-
  - Media Matters for America, 10/02/2007-
  - Media Mobilizing Project, 5/18/2011-
  - MediaFilter, 3/26/2010-
  - Michael Munk, 7/8/2011-
  - Mother Jones, 2/13/2012-
  - National Radio Project, 5/3/2012-
  - New York City Independent Media Center, 10/02/2007-
  - Pacifica Radio Archives, 8/22/2009-
  - PacificaFoundation.org, 08/08/2009-
  - Paper Tiger Television, 03/18/2009-
  - People's Production House, 10/15/2011-
  - PR Watch, 10/02/2007-
  - Progressive Radio Network, 08/16/2009-
  - Prometheus Radio Project, 3/5/2010-
  - Radio Populares, 10/12/2011-
  - Roar Magazine, 4/1/2012-
  - Rolling Stone: Politics, 10/18/2011-
  - Sanctuary for Independent Media, 3/26/2010-
  - SourceWatch, 7/13/2011-
  - Take Back WBAI Radio, 5/6/2011-
  - Talking Points Memo, 04/22/2009-
  - The Huffington Post, 11/18/2010
  - Think Progress, 10/07/2011-
  - Thom Hartmann Program, 4/26/2012-
  - TomDispatch, 10/14/2011-
  - Truthdig: Drilling Beneath the Headlines, 4/8/2010-
  - Truthout Originals, 07/28/2009-
  - WBAI Radio (New York, NY), 10/03/2007-
  - We the Blog, 12/06/2008
  - We the People, 1/07/2012-
  - WPFW 89.3 FM, 7/16/2011-
  - Z Net, 10/02/2007-